<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Honorable Mentions on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/</link><description>Recent content in Honorable Mentions on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alien</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/alien/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/alien/</guid><description>From the silent darkness comes a beam of light. A weathered face is looking down on us, the eyes narrowing ever so slightly. Over the shoulder of the onlooker comes a cry, “Over here!” Some of us look over in the direction from which the booming voice comes. Others are simply too exhausted to even open their eyes. Their skulls gently rocking atop their spines as the bitter waves push and pull below us, enticing us downward.</description></item><item><title>Angelique MacLeod</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/angelique-macleod/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/angelique-macleod/</guid><description>Atlantic Monthly The Inspirational Women profile Angelique MacLeod
Interview by Sophie O’Mara 19th August 2052
This month we are featuring one of the many remarkable women who have steered us through these incredibly challenging times, transitioning into a new way of living with nature and each other. She is Angelique MacLeod also known as Anne, a witch, who has been a powerful leader instrumental in creating the independent Uist Islands’ Coöperative in the Outer Hebrides, Scotland and the worldwide Islands’ Consortium.</description></item><item><title>Covid-19</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/covid-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/covid-19/</guid><description>Age 10
Hi, I am a germ. You might have heard of me. My name is Covid-19, I was born in 2020. Lots of people hate me because I killed them while they were infected. But I think I am pretty cool because lots of people want to destroy me. But they can’t! Hahaha (evil laugh). Now scientists are trying to realize who I am and they want to invent vaccines to get rid of me.</description></item><item><title>Dream of Turtle’s Future</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/dream-of-turtles-future/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/dream-of-turtles-future/</guid><description>Age 11
My name is Kimi. I have a friend named Taffy. We live together in a cozy house. We both like turtles, so we have a pet turtle named Noemi in our house.
One day, when I was eating dinner with Taffy, the TV turned on, and we both saw the news “The turtles in the sea are dying, please save them.” Then the TV turned off again. I looked at Taffy, she looked scared.</description></item><item><title>Mother of Peace</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/mother-of-peace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/mother-of-peace/</guid><description>Age 11
“Little Mariah, this is a crystal ball that will change EVERYTHING, please use it for good and not for evil when I pass away honey.”
Little Mariah was young, too young to understand anything her granddad said, so she just nodded and smiled innocently. Her granddad sighed, knowing that he wouldn’t be able to see the world in full peace. Still, knowing that Mariah could see the sight brought a smile to his old, tired face.</description></item><item><title>Save Our Earth</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/save-our-earth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/save-our-earth/</guid><description>Everyone knows driving cars are way easier than walking. But, the truth starts here.
A little girl named Bella is watching the TV, and it was talking about air pollution. Bella said to her pet dog Doggy “This is a very big problem to our Earth. We have to do something.”
A voice from behind says “What are you doing?? It is already 10 o’clock?? You have class tomorrow. Today is Monday.</description></item><item><title>Save the World</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/save-the-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/save-the-world/</guid><description>Age 7
I am a cat sleeping in the warm sunlight, enjoying the breeze. Boom! I hear the sound of bombs. Boom! Boom! I run and run until I see the most horrible sight anyone has ever seen.
There are tanks, military helicopters and soldiers holding guns.
I suddenly feel someone pick me up. I look up to see a young girl. She takes me into her arms and runs as fast as she can.</description></item><item><title>Shell</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/shell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/shell/</guid><description>“Come back here!”
The man waved to a little boy running to the beach behind a group of older kids. The child ignored him. The man shrugged, after days of rain there was no keeping the kids still. He walked back in and the door closed behind him.
The kids&amp;rsquo; laughter was still within earshot, the sun in his face, and the old man extended his legs. The golden light was filling the courtyard but through his worn-out jeans, he could feel the cold stone he was sitting on.</description></item><item><title>Take Care of Earth</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/take-care-of-earth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/take-care-of-earth/</guid><description>Age 7
Once upon a time, I saw a man using an ax to cut down trees. It made me feel sad. I yelled, “Don’t use that ax! Cutting down trees will destroy the forest.”
The man said “okay, I’ll stop.”
Then I saw that there were some flowers dying. They didn’t have water. So, I used some water and poured it on the flower. I also planted some more flowers and trees.</description></item><item><title>Taking Care of Endangered Leopards</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/taking-care-of-endangered-leopards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/taking-care-of-endangered-leopards/</guid><description>Age 10
One day, as I am walking by a farm, I see a very big and beautiful grassland. There are more than 63,833 chickens. So I can go to the farm and eat chicken everyday for breakfast. Today, I am doing the same thing as every day when I wake up. I am very hungry, so I jump into the farm and eat the chickens. It tastes so yummy and good!</description></item><item><title>The Beach Clean Up</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-beach-clean-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-beach-clean-up/</guid><description>Age 8
One day, my mom tells me a story about a beach covered in trash. I started to think about it and thought maybe there are some people who aren’t very nice. I think I need to help clean the beach.
My mom says, “You can go pick up trash at the beach.”
I thought that was a good idea. I told my mom that I would good tomorrow since I didn’t have class that day.</description></item><item><title>The Black Forest</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-black-forest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-black-forest/</guid><description>Age 10
Nowadays, we see a lot of people polluting the environment. The environmental problem has become bigger and bigger. The plastic problem is also a big problem for the environment. Now, I am going to tell you an environmental story.
A long, long time ago, there was a girl called Mini, and Mini liked to play around in the forest. One day, Mini was playing with her friend, Lili. They were both born in the same year on the same day, so many people called them twins.</description></item><item><title>The First Stone</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-first-stone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-first-stone/</guid><description>Tessa was playing at the edge of the boundary line when she first stumbled upon it. Hundreds of polished stones arranged into interconnecting circles at a flat clearing on the hilltop. Against the chestnut and walnut tree bark, it looked as though it was floating. A chilly breeze stirred up the leaves and whirled around her.
Her uncle had told her not to go there.
‘Don’t touch it,’ Tessa could hear his warning voice in her mind.</description></item><item><title>The Gift to Earth</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-gift-to-earth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-gift-to-earth/</guid><description>Age 9
One day, there was a young boy. He said, “I want to give the Earth a gift.” He thought about what he could give the Earth and then he decided to build 100 parks. His parks had colorful flowers and trees. The air was good. The boy was happy with his gift to Earth, even the animals had a good home.
The Earth is our friend. We need parks and animals to live in it.</description></item><item><title>The Last Vaquitas</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-last-vaquitas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-last-vaquitas/</guid><description>Age 10
I’m swimming in the deep, blue ocean. I feel alone because I haven’t seen any other vaquitas for a very long time. All of this is because of illegal fishing. The fishermen keep fishing us and we are almost extinct now. There are only around 10 of us left in the world! This is also because of the pollution and spread of diseases. Just like right now, I see a ton of trash right in front of me.</description></item><item><title>The Lost Home</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-lost-home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-lost-home/</guid><description>Age 8
My home was once beautiful. But now, it’s full of trash. I still look up and see the sun shining bright orange and red across the beautiful sea. I am a little crab and this is where I live.
I always need to find a new home. I don’t feel comfortable and there aren’t many choices. I once lived in a plastic cup for a little while. I didn’t really like it there.</description></item><item><title>The Poor Butterfly</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-poor-butterfly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-poor-butterfly/</guid><description>Age 7
If you were a bug, you would have a very sad life because some people kill bugs to make imprints. Some people catch bugs to bring them home. So, bugs are in danger and we need to protect them.
There was once the most beautiful butterfly living happily by herself, enjoying the pretty flowers. One day, a man caught her and took her home. He wanted to keep her in a jar and watch her every day.</description></item><item><title>The Talking Trash Cans</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-talking-trash-cans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-talking-trash-cans/</guid><description>Age 6
The trash cans are everywhere. They can talk and eat paper. Some trash cans can even eat plastic. They also teach us lessons. The trash cans say, “Don’t throw trash on the floor, please! Throw trash in the trash cans!”
The trash cans tell us their job is to keep the Earth clean. At night, the trash cans don’t sleep and the trash cans talk to people about not throwing trash on the floor.</description></item><item><title>The Trash Cans</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-trash-cans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-trash-cans/</guid><description>Age 7
I see trash cans flying in the sky. They can walk, laugh and collect trash in the air. They can turn into very small bins. They can eat plastic, paper, cans, shoes and books.
The trash cans can fly very fast. If they eat crayons, they will be very angry. They don’t like crayons! If they eat erasers, they eat erasers, they will be very happy. They like erasers!</description></item><item><title>Wolves in Yellowstone</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/wolves-in-yellowstone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/wolves-in-yellowstone/</guid><description>Age 9
Today I see many people holding a sign that reads Wolves don’t belong in Yellowstone.
“What are you doing?” I ask. “Wolves are good!”
The man holding the sign put it down. “Wolves are not good! They kill ranchers and farmers’ livestock. If we don’t kick the wolves out of Yellowstone, we won’t have any meat to eat!”
I was so shocked. I felt that I needed to save the wolves in Yellowstone.</description></item></channel></rss>