<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>XR Wordsmiths’ Top Picks on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2021/stories/xr-picks/</link><description>Recent content in XR Wordsmiths’ Top Picks on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2021/stories/xr-picks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Park</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/the-park/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/the-park/</guid><description>The child’s face was cold, with a coating of frost and an icicle hanging off the end of her chin.
The sun glinted off her forehead in fits and starts as it peeked through the clouds, but it was too little to warm her.
It was January, after all, and it had been a cloudy winter.
Jules always cut through the park on her way to work, but she liked it best this time of year.</description></item><item><title>The Singer of Seeds</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/singer-of-seeds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/singer-of-seeds/</guid><description>Maïa climbs up the ladder and tries to sit next to me with as little noise as possible.
“You’re late,” I mutter, and it comes out more annoyed than I am.
“I know,” she whispers, crossing her legs on the sandwood boards to my mat, as she has forgotten hers again.
We stare at the landscape before us, a hand risen up to our faces, covering the left eye. Our right eye is fixed on that jagged line of mountain crests on the horizon, where the purple haze is shifting into a warm peach light.</description></item></channel></rss>