<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/overview/</guid><description>The 2023 XR Solarpunk Showcase is now open for entries! In 2021, Extinction Rebellion launched its first ever Solarpunk Showcase; a global fiction writing competition organised by XR Wordsmiths. We had such an incredible response that we are organising another one. And so without further ado, we announce that the 2023 XR Solarpunk Showcase is live and ready for your entries!
Once again, we want to use our collective imagination as a tool against the climate and ecological emergency.</description></item><item><title>2023 Showcase FAQ</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/faq/</guid><description>Q: Who are XR Wordsmiths?
A: We are a band/collective of writers who are deeply concerned with the climate and ecological emergency facing us all. We are a part of Extinction Rebellion, and hail from all over the world. Our writing is one way we battle against this emergency — we hope it spurs curiosity, concern, inspiration, reflection, love, rage, and also action. You’ll find all kinds of writing here, and a diversity of voices and styles, to remind us of the diversity of humankind and of our beautiful living earth.</description></item><item><title>2023 Showcase Submission Instructions</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/submission-instructions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/submission-instructions/</guid><description>With your Solarpunk vision for the planetary future in mind, please write a short story of up to 2,500 words and send it as an email (or Word/ PDF/ Google Doc email attachment) to XR Wordsmiths (xr-writers@protonmail.com) with the subject line ‘Solarpunk Showcase Submission 2023’.
Writers under the age of 18, please have your parents fill out a consent form for your entry. You can click on it here and please attach it with your submission.</description></item><item><title>50 Shades of Green</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/penned-by-the-wordsmiths/50-shades-of-green/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/penned-by-the-wordsmiths/50-shades-of-green/</guid><description>Castor looked around him at the wilderness he was helping to rebuild. There was a long way to go - but it was starting to look better. What had been a barren wasteland with a stagnant lake fed by a miserable network of anorexic streams was slowly blossoming into green wilderness. Indeed, the rewilding project had got to the point where further species were being reintroduced. Among the first species reintroduced was the beaver, and this was where he came in.</description></item><item><title>About SolarPunk</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/about/solarpunk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/about/solarpunk/</guid><description>Solarpunk is all about envisioning a planetary future in which humanity, non-human nature, and technology co-exist in harmony. It can be described as a social movement and a lifestyle, as well as a genre of literature, art, fashion, music, and architecture.
Solarpunk’s main ethos lies in finding solutions for a more sustainable and egalitarian world through rebellion against the status quo. Its distinctive aesthetics are bright, clean, and futuristic, often reminiscent of sci-fi themes and involving iconography such as vertical gardens, birds of paradise, waterfalls, futuristic architecture, and indigenous art.</description></item><item><title>About the Artwork</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/about/artwork/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/about/artwork/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About the Judges</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/about/judges/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/about/judges/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About the Prizes</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/about/prizes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/about/prizes/</guid><description>The winning stories from the 2021 Showcase will be published in Solarpunk Magazine, Solarpunk Society Magazine, Shoreline of Infinity Science-Fiction Magazine, by the Rapid Transition Alliance, and in Extinction Rebellion publications. All winning stories were illustrated by a team of artists spread across the globe. The artwork has been published on this website.
Our other 2021 prizes included full scholarships to Terra.do (the world’s first online global climate school), in-person workshops by Taiwanese sustainable design education enterprise TOTES &amp;amp; TEES, interviews and podcast versions of the stories by Solarpunk Magazine, interviews with Ecofictology vlogger Lovis Geier, 1-to-1 mentorship with eco-writer and poet Helen Moore, animal adoption kits, wildflower seeds, Solarpunk Magazine annual subscriptions, certificates, and of course - books!</description></item><item><title>About the Showcase</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/about/showcase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/about/showcase/</guid><description>The XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase is Extinction Rebellion’s first global short story contest for all ages.
The project rides the wave of the Solarpunk movement and aims to use the power of collective imagination as a tool against the climate and ecological emergency. Through radical re-imaginings of the world, we can get closer to creating a future that is positive and healthy for all life.
2021’s Showcase was this project’s first iteration.</description></item><item><title>About XR Wordsmiths</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/about/xr-wordsmiths/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/about/xr-wordsmiths/</guid><description>We are a band/collective of writers who are deeply concerned with the climate and ecological emergency facing us all. We are a part of Extinction Rebellion, and hail from all over the world.
Our writing is one way we battle against this emergency— we hope it spurs curiosity, concern, inspiration, reflection, love, rage, and also action.
Check out the XR Wordsmiths blog, where you’ll find all kinds of writing and a diversity of voices and styles, to remind us of the diversity of humankind and our beautiful living earth.</description></item><item><title>Adder’s Crystal</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/19+/adders-crystal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/19+/adders-crystal/</guid><description>Adder stared quizzically at the dried and brittle thing in her line of vision, which had been a flower only three months before. A cold northern wind blew the delicate husk of its stem from side to side like an old disjointed fence post caught in a tornado.
A great mass rose from over the horizon. Lifted by a force as incomprehensible to Adder as the changing of the seasons, it charged into the open sky and disappeared.</description></item><item><title>Alien</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/alien/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/alien/</guid><description>From the silent darkness comes a beam of light. A weathered face is looking down on us, the eyes narrowing ever so slightly. Over the shoulder of the onlooker comes a cry, “Over here!” Some of us look over in the direction from which the booming voice comes. Others are simply too exhausted to even open their eyes. Their skulls gently rocking atop their spines as the bitter waves push and pull below us, enticing us downward.</description></item><item><title>Amal</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/penned-by-the-wordsmiths/amal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/penned-by-the-wordsmiths/amal/</guid><description>She stretched her right leg out before her, gingerly dipping her big toe into the water. The first touch was cool, making her gasp and giggle in surprise, but it quickly melted into a warm welcome from the marsh water. She lowered her foot in further, throwing her arms wide and grasping a clump of reeds to balance— ever careful not to drop one precious date from her colorful reed-woven basket.</description></item><item><title>Angelique MacLeod</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/angelique-macleod/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/angelique-macleod/</guid><description>Atlantic Monthly The Inspirational Women profile Angelique MacLeod
Interview by Sophie O’Mara 19th August 2052
This month we are featuring one of the many remarkable women who have steered us through these incredibly challenging times, transitioning into a new way of living with nature and each other. She is Angelique MacLeod also known as Anne, a witch, who has been a powerful leader instrumental in creating the independent Uist Islands’ Coöperative in the Outer Hebrides, Scotland and the worldwide Islands’ Consortium.</description></item><item><title>Automata Albatross</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/automata-albatross/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/automata-albatross/</guid><description>The albatross almost struck Akila as it fell. With a metallic shriek, it plummeted from the empty gray sky to shatter at her feet, wires spilling onto the slick cement of the sidewalk. She stood frozen in shock as tendrils of steam coolant curled through her braids, its beak chattering eerily as it shuddered into stillness. A dead albatross was very bad luck, her offshore studies professor had told her. Perhaps he would know what to do with it.</description></item><item><title>Automata Albatross</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/automata-albatross/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/automata-albatross/</guid><description>The albatross almost struck Akila as it fell. With a metallic shriek, it plummeted from the empty gray sky to shatter at her feet, wires spilling onto the slick cement of the sidewalk. She stood frozen in shock as tendrils of steam coolant curled through her braids, its beak chattering eerily as it shuddered into stillness. A dead albatross was very bad luck, her offshore studies professor had told her. Perhaps he would know what to do with it.</description></item><item><title>Blood Oil</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/blood-oil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/blood-oil/</guid><description>I walk through the tall grass, it whispers against my legs. My bare feet press against the soft soil and I hear Mother Earth calling out to me, crying for help. Along the horizon, I see the oil pipeline cutting across the forest, swaths of trees chopped down in its wake. A scar cutting across Mother Earth, drawing the blood from within her to the surface. Blood flowing forth, a torrent of blood.</description></item><item><title>Blood Oil</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/blood-oil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/blood-oil/</guid><description>I walk through the tall grass, it whispers against my legs. My bare feet press against the soft soil and I hear Mother Earth calling out to me, crying for help. Along the horizon, I see the oil pipeline cutting across the forest, swaths of trees chopped down in its wake. A scar cutting across Mother Earth, drawing the blood from within her to the surface. Blood flowing forth, a torrent of blood.</description></item><item><title>Chris Haughton</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/judges/chris/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/judges/chris/</guid><description>Chris is the brilliant author and illustrator of seven children’s books including “A Bit Lost”, “Oh No George!”, and “Well Done Mummy Penguin”. His stories and illustrations have captured the imaginations of children across the world and have been translated into 35 languages! Chris is passionate about creating a better world for children, and has created a social business, madebynode.com to connect design and fair trade and make rugs and toys.</description></item><item><title>City Starlight &amp; The Cemetery</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/city-starlight-cemetery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/city-starlight-cemetery/</guid><description>City Starlight
I can feel the anxiety radiating through me as I paddle the kayak with slow, wide motions. What am I anxious about, you ask? Nothing in particular. That’s what is so frustrating about it- I feel it all the time, even on perfectly nice, ordinary days. I take a deep breath and try to absorb some of the tranquility of the environment around me. The sun is almost done rising, the sky a fiery orange, with only the barest strokes of indigo around the edges alluding to the fact that it had been dark just a few minutes ago.</description></item><item><title>City Starlight &amp; The Cemetery</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/city-starlight-cemetery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/city-starlight-cemetery/</guid><description>City Starlight
I can feel the anxiety radiating through me as I paddle the kayak with slow, wide motions. What am I anxious about, you ask? Nothing in particular. That’s what is so frustrating about it- I feel it all the time, even on perfectly nice, ordinary days. I take a deep breath and try to absorb some of the tranquility of the environment around me. The sun is almost done rising, the sky a fiery orange, with only the barest strokes of indigo around the edges alluding to the fact that it had been dark just a few minutes ago.</description></item><item><title>Colouring In</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/penned-by-the-wordsmiths/colouring-in/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/penned-by-the-wordsmiths/colouring-in/</guid><description>“I think you’re a pink,” said Leaf with a smile. The boy glanced at her and looked away towards the window. She watched him for another few seconds. “I’ll change the leaves on your dressing in a bit,” she said. “You’ll soon be back swinging from branch to branch, like a gorilla.” She beat her chest lightly and gave a few little howls. The boy looked round at her. “That’s wolf,” he said.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/contact/</guid><description>If you have any questions or ideas for collaboration,
please reach us at xr-writers@protonmail.com.</description></item><item><title>Covid-19</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/covid-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/covid-19/</guid><description>Age 10
Hi, I am a germ. You might have heard of me. My name is Covid-19, I was born in 2020. Lots of people hate me because I killed them while they were infected. But I think I am pretty cool because lots of people want to destroy me. But they can’t! Hahaha (evil laugh). Now scientists are trying to realize who I am and they want to invent vaccines to get rid of me.</description></item><item><title>Donate</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/donate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/donate/</guid><description>The 2021 Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase was only made possible through the incredible hard work and generosity of everyone involved: judges, illustrators, graphic designers, web developers, prize donors - the list goes on.
We were amazed to see how far this project went without any official fundraising, and are excited to see how much bigger and better it can get in later iterations. As such, we have set up a Chuffed.org page where you can donate to help fund the next Showcase - any amount appreciated and welcome!</description></item><item><title>Dream of Turtle’s Future</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/dream-of-turtles-future/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/dream-of-turtles-future/</guid><description>Age 11
My name is Kimi. I have a friend named Taffy. We live together in a cozy house. We both like turtles, so we have a pet turtle named Noemi in our house.
One day, when I was eating dinner with Taffy, the TV turned on, and we both saw the news “The turtles in the sea are dying, please save them.” Then the TV turned off again. I looked at Taffy, she looked scared.</description></item><item><title>Dylan Cooler</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/dylan-cooler/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/dylan-cooler/</guid><description>I’m Dylan, the greatest inventor of all time. One of my greatest Inventions is a giant water-powered air conditioner with a global warming detector, I named it- Dylan Cooler! So why did I invent this machine?
I genuinely love animals, especially polar bears. They live in the North Pole where there is a lot of ice. They need this ice to feed, rest and raise families. However the ice is melting because of global warming.</description></item><item><title>Dylan Cooler</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/dylan-cooler/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/dylan-cooler/</guid><description>I’m Dylan, the greatest inventor of all time. One of my greatest Inventions is a giant water-powered air conditioner with a global warming detector, I named it- Dylan Cooler! So why did I invent this machine?
I genuinely love animals, especially polar bears. They live in the North Pole where there is a lot of ice. They need this ice to feed, rest and raise families. However the ice is melting because of global warming.</description></item><item><title>Gabby's First Kiss</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/gabby/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/gabby/</guid><description>Gabby nearly knocked her mother over as she rushed through the kitchen and out the front door. Outside, she paused to look over the horizon. Her home, like all the homes in Bahía del Paraíso, sat high in the air; protected from the floods that were a regular part of life in their small coastal community. From her perch, she could easily see all the way to the bay. In the early morning sunlight, the mangroves along the water’s edge glowed as if they were on fire.</description></item><item><title>Gabby's First Kiss</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/gabby/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/gabby/</guid><description>Gabby nearly knocked her mother over as she rushed through the kitchen and out the front door. Outside, she paused to look over the horizon. Her home, like all the homes in Bahía del Paraíso, sat high in the air; protected from the floods that were a regular part of life in their small coastal community. From her perch, she could easily see all the way to the bay. In the early morning sunlight, the mangroves along the water’s edge glowed as if they were on fire.</description></item><item><title>Green Wall</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/green-wall/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/green-wall/</guid><description>The light from the tall window glinted on the pincers. Between their finely-engineered points, Lin held a tiny, red-leaved oxalis. With a purposeful prod, she inserted it into the wad of sphagnum moss where the other red-leaved species were already taking root. Further back along the wall, where she had first begun, tides of green tendrils lapped against jade fractals. Glossy weeping figs sheltered verdant ferns, whose close-held scent reminded Lin of woodland streams.</description></item><item><title>Green Wall</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/green-wall/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/green-wall/</guid><description>The light from the tall window glinted on the pincers. Between their finely-engineered points, Lin held a tiny, red-leaved oxalis. With a purposeful prod, she inserted it into the wad of sphagnum moss where the other red-leaved species were already taking root. Further back along the wall, where she had first begun, tides of green tendrils lapped against jade fractals. Glossy weeping figs sheltered verdant ferns, whose close-held scent reminded Lin of woodland streams.</description></item><item><title>Green Witch</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/green-witch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/green-witch/</guid><description>Between sunset and starlight spans the twilight, and that is when we witches gather to dance in the garden. Live by the sun, love by the moon, so goes the old saying. A catchy soundbite, a t-shirt slogan, but truer now than ever before, as the solar panels swallow greedily the last peach-red-golden rays on the horizon, as the city sighs its relief and prepares to settle into slumber. The suburbs come alive with a patchwork of lights.</description></item><item><title>Green Witch</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/green-witch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/green-witch/</guid><description>Between sunset and starlight spans the twilight, and that is when we witches gather to dance in the garden. Live by the sun, love by the moon, so goes the old saying. A catchy soundbite, a t-shirt slogan, but truer now than ever before, as the solar panels swallow greedily the last peach-red-golden rays on the horizon, as the city sighs its relief and prepares to settle into slumber. The suburbs come alive with a patchwork of lights.</description></item><item><title>Hanging Gardens of Babylon</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/hanging-gardens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/hanging-gardens/</guid><description>“What we’re looking at here,” he pulled the map down slightly, “is the only man-made wonder of the world to exist twice. Every other thing on this old list has been destroyed.”
We both took a look at the gates guarding the Hanging Gardens of Babylon. The posts were clearly composed of scrap metal forged into single, twisting rods. The gates reached high above our heads, weaving into each other like so many gleaming branches.</description></item><item><title>Hanging Gardens of Babylon</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/hanging-gardens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/hanging-gardens/</guid><description>“What we’re looking at here,” he pulled the map down slightly, “is the only man-made wonder of the world to exist twice. Every other thing on this old list has been destroyed.”
We both took a look at the gates guarding the Hanging Gardens of Babylon. The posts were clearly composed of scrap metal forged into single, twisting rods. The gates reached high above our heads, weaving into each other like so many gleaming branches.</description></item><item><title>Honourable Mentions</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/honorable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/honorable/</guid><description>Utopia in the Sewers
by Özkan Akman
Green Wall
Clare Harvey
The Well-Trodden Path
by Tom Jubert
Rooted Ritual
by Charlie McKay Seaweed
by Hazel Morfett
The Hanging Gardens of Babylon
by Rebekah Neuberger
Meeting at the Giant Mushroom
by Jeremy Parker
Sooty
by Luke Lanyon-Hog</description></item><item><title>Hospitalized in Utopia</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/hospitalized-utopia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/hospitalized-utopia/</guid><description>Diana looked out the window at the sky. It was a good sky, she liked looking at it, but she couldn’t look at much else. If she turned her head the other way she could see only pale blue walls, medical equipment, and a glimpse of that machine in the hallway that went beep! beep! beep! She couldn’t imagine what it did—and she had tried.
Supposedly her window actually had a lovely view of half the green city.</description></item><item><title>Hospitalized in Utopia</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/hospitalized-utopia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/hospitalized-utopia/</guid><description>Diana looked out the window at the sky. It was a good sky, she liked looking at it, but she couldn’t look at much else. If she turned her head the other way she could see only pale blue walls, medical equipment, and a glimpse of that machine in the hallway that went beep! beep! beep! She couldn’t imagine what it did—and she had tried.
Supposedly her window actually had a lovely view of half the green city.</description></item><item><title>Jade Baker</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/judges/jade/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/judges/jade/</guid><description>Jade Baker is a primary school teacher in Catford, London where she leads English. She has taught in Lewisham for a decade and holds an MA in Children’s Literature from Goldsmiths. She has a long history as an activist, starting at a protest against a coal-fired power station in Nottinghamshire and then the student movement in 2010 against the increase in tuition fees. She is a representative of the NEU.</description></item><item><title>Joe Tankersley</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/judges/joe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/judges/joe/</guid><description>Joe Tankersley is a wandering storyteller, futurist, and advocate for better tomorrows. His previous careers include bartending, filmmaking, and creating magical places for Walt Disney Imagineering.</description></item><item><title>Kara Laing</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/judges/kara/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/judges/kara/</guid><description>Dr. Kara Laing is an engineer who has been a member of XR Engineers and Scientists for Extinction Rebellion (who aim to help scientists with their activism and activists with their science) since 2018. After completing a Ph.D. in Applied Mathematics, she started working as a mechanical engineer, building computer models to help designers make their products better, and now looking for ways to make them more sustainable. In her spare time, she loves immersing herself in the other worlds that books bring.</description></item><item><title>Katrina Eilender</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/judges/katrina/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/judges/katrina/</guid><description>Katrina Eilender is one of our 2021 Showcase Winners!</description></item><item><title>Lea Cortas</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/judges/lea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/judges/lea/</guid><description>Lea Cortas grew up in Lebanon and is now attending Amsterdam University College where she studies film. Growing up in the mountains of Lebanon, Lea has always had a deep appreciation of nature and a love for reading and writing. She has worked on sustainability projects through high school and has her own YouTube channel.</description></item><item><title>Less Fear</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/12-18/less-fear/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/12-18/less-fear/</guid><description>JANUARY 14TH, 2123
The green vines climb and reach the top of the city’s skyline. Leaves and branches bursting out of the windows and balconies of a bright skyscraper – absorbing the light of the sun to power all of its inhabitants. There’s just as much life of flora as there is the life of people in the building. I look across the park to my right and see how the people have almost merged with the many native trees and plants that occupy the park, because there are always more plants than people – wherever you go in the city, whatever street, alley or hallway.</description></item><item><title>Lichenicolous</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/runners-up/lichenicolous/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/runners-up/lichenicolous/</guid><description>“Estimated high UV later in the week.” Eloise frowned slightly and glanced up. “I think we ought to up-regulate.” She crossed the room to the lichen interface and tapped on the screen.
Tasneem looked up. “Auto not recommending?”
“Mmm. No. But it’s been reasonably high anyway, and last time there was a high few days the photobiont suffered.”
“Okay, I trust you, if you think it’s best.”
Eloise programmed in increased UV protection and pressed send.</description></item><item><title>Lovis Geier</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/judges/lovis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/judges/lovis/</guid><description>Dr. Lovis Geier is an ecologist who loves to incorporate her nerdiness into her works of eco-fantasy and vice versa, incorporating storytelling and fiction into her science communication work. In her academic life, she focuses on population ecology, dispersal, and animal movement in the marine environment - all in front of a laptop because she works in silica, meaning building computer models to do all kinds of fancy things. Her writing life is mostly lived on her YouTube channel Ecofictology, where she talks all about reading and writing eco-fiction and how it can be used as a science communication tool.</description></item><item><title>Meeting at the Giant Mushroom</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/meeting-mushrooms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/meeting-mushrooms/</guid><description>Lisa Kendrick brushed down her smart, grey skirt suit, then smoothed her perfectly styled hair. Pausing, she checked her makeup and gave her hair a second glance, then she nodded, satisfied that she still looked like she’d just stepped out of a salon. Then she stopped and thought. Then she sat down.
“I’m overdressed,” she told herself. Damn. She hadn’t wanted to fret, but there she was, fretting. She wanted to impress but she was probably going about it in completely the wrong way.</description></item><item><title>Meeting at the Giant Mushroom</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/meeting-mushrooms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/meeting-mushrooms/</guid><description>Lisa Kendrick brushed down her smart, grey skirt suit, then smoothed her perfectly styled hair. Pausing, she checked her makeup and gave her hair a second glance, then she nodded, satisfied that she still looked like she’d just stepped out of a salon. Then she stopped and thought. Then she sat down.
“I’m overdressed,” she told herself. Damn. She hadn’t wanted to fret, but there she was, fretting. She wanted to impress but she was probably going about it in completely the wrong way.</description></item><item><title>Mily's Adventure of Future Houses</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/runners-up/milys-adventure-of-future-houses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/runners-up/milys-adventure-of-future-houses/</guid><description>Once there was a girl called Mily. She was a very kind child; she cared about the Earth a lot. She knew that the earth was turning warm because people kept cutting down trees and there will be no trees to give us clean oxygen.
One day, when she was walking on the street, she saw a small, weird creature passing through her and left a pretty gazing ball in front of her.</description></item><item><title>Mona Damluji</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/judges/mona/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/judges/mona/</guid><description>Dr. Mona Damluji is an Assistant Professor at the University of California, Santa Barbara studying oil culture and cinema history in the Middle East. She is the author of the amazing children’s book “Together”, a story of the power of collective action.</description></item><item><title>Mori</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/artwork/mori/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/artwork/mori/</guid><description>Mori is a digital artist from a small city in Chile. After studying Illustration and Graphic Design in DuocUC, she’s worked on several freelance projects: drawing characters for TV animations, illustrations for books and websites, t-shirt designs, prints, and posters. She’s also collaborated with several artists and participated in local Illustration fairs. Nowadays she is focused on creating new merch with the Dream.Mori signature. Mori is inspired by dreams, the unconscious and intrusive thoughts, which she combines to create evocative sensations through a digital canvas.</description></item><item><title>Mother of Peace</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/mother-of-peace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/mother-of-peace/</guid><description>Age 11
“Little Mariah, this is a crystal ball that will change EVERYTHING, please use it for good and not for evil when I pass away honey.”
Little Mariah was young, too young to understand anything her granddad said, so she just nodded and smiled innocently. Her granddad sighed, knowing that he wouldn’t be able to see the world in full peace. Still, knowing that Mariah could see the sight brought a smile to his old, tired face.</description></item><item><title>Mr. Smith’s Unpleasant Last Day</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/runners-up/mr-smiths-unpleasant-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/runners-up/mr-smiths-unpleasant-day/</guid><description>“Shit!” Aldous Smith always took care walking through his neighborhood’s allotment. The tall grass and wildflower patches made the long trek to his Ford Fiesta a ‘perilous’ journey - in his mind. He always took care when plodding through the grass. But this time Aldous stepped right in it.
‘Probably a fox’, he thought ‘checking on the honeycombs.’
25 years ago, this space was a parking lot. It was only a three minute walk from Aldous’s front door to his car.</description></item><item><title>Neil Walker</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/judges/nmwalker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/judges/nmwalker/</guid><description>Neil Walker is a retired health data scientist, now part of the UK&amp;rsquo;s Extinction Rebellion&amp;rsquo;s Data Analysis &amp;amp; Insights Circle, which aims to put the evidence into evidence-based climate activism. Having borrowed his mother&amp;rsquo;s library lending card - this was before YA literature was a thing - he has read voraciously since he was able, choosing books without much attention to genre. He now has a bad (or is that good?</description></item><item><title>Of Creatures &amp; Caretakers</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/runners-up/of-creatures-and-caretakers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/runners-up/of-creatures-and-caretakers/</guid><description>Network whisperings are delighting her soul. She reaches out to her kin and exchanges sustenance through the embrace of wide-reaching arms. A new bloom is mutually shared, and layers of soil are teeming with life, infinitely invigorating.
“We are growing,” they whisper, taking her many hands to guide her. She feels the pinpricks of smaller meshwork connecting with her own. There, supported by many loving arms a new born oak sapling pokes its head through the soil, moist with morning dew.</description></item><item><title>Return to Kiribati</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/return-kiribati/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/return-kiribati/</guid><description>Only the cold, untwinkling speck of a space station pierced the darkness between the thinning cumulus and the churning ink-black sea.
The storm sail billowed and creaked, water thundered like rapids between the three hulls, and Kraken hydrofoiled a metre clear of the water, slicing through the detritus of coconuts and disintegrating plastic that had been whipped into a seething broth by the Pacific cyclone wind. My eyes combed the ebony veils of rain for signs of pursuit, but the outcasts’ ramshackle vessel couldn’t have made it through.</description></item><item><title>Return to Kiribati</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/return-kiribati/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/return-kiribati/</guid><description>Only the cold, untwinkling speck of a space station pierced the darkness between the thinning cumulus and the churning ink-black sea.
The storm sail billowed and creaked, water thundered like rapids between the three hulls, and Kraken hydrofoiled a metre clear of the water, slicing through the detritus of coconuts and disintegrating plastic that had been whipped into a seething broth by the Pacific cyclone wind. My eyes combed the ebony veils of rain for signs of pursuit, but the outcasts’ ramshackle vessel couldn’t have made it through.</description></item><item><title>Rita Fei</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/artwork/rita-fei/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/artwork/rita-fei/</guid><description>Rita Fei is an illustrator based in Vancouver, BC, and who graduated from Emily Carr University of Art and Design. She loves creating characters and worlds for the wonderfully broad spectrum of speculative fiction, and had a piece published in Spectrum 26. She is currently working full-time as a designer at Bardel Entertainment, and occasionally as a freelancer for various projects. Her entry for the Solarpunk Atomhawk competition was chosen as the title image for this Showcase.</description></item><item><title>Rooted Ritual</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/rooted-ritual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/rooted-ritual/</guid><description>Paulo awoke to the sound of sizzling tomatoes being cooked by his grandmother in the kitchen of their two-bedroom apartment. Several seconds of serene silence passed before she sweetly beckoned him for breakfast.
“Paulo…. Paulo” she called, followed by several other soft murmurings that he couldn’t quite discern.
The air was crisp as beams of light filtered through the mosaic gaps of his slightly ajar window. He stretched, stirred, twisted and eventually rose to peer out across the vast landscape of pinkish clouds that were warmed by a golden coat from the early morning sun.</description></item><item><title>Rooted Ritual</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/rooted-ritual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/rooted-ritual/</guid><description>Paulo awoke to the sound of sizzling tomatoes being cooked by his grandmother in the kitchen of their two-bedroom apartment. Several seconds of serene silence passed before she sweetly beckoned him for breakfast.
“Paulo…. Paulo” she called, followed by several other soft murmurings that he couldn’t quite discern.
The air was crisp as beams of light filtered through the mosaic gaps of his slightly ajar window. He stretched, stirred, twisted and eventually rose to peer out across the vast landscape of pinkish clouds that were warmed by a golden coat from the early morning sun.</description></item><item><title>Runners Up</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/runners-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/runners-up/</guid><description>Hospitalized in Utopia
by Caroline Ailanthus
Wall of Flowers
by Septimus Crowe Automata Albatross
by Robin Happel
Return to Kiribati
by Alexandra Porter Green Witch
by Katrina Townsend</description></item><item><title>Save Our Earth</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/save-our-earth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/save-our-earth/</guid><description>Everyone knows driving cars are way easier than walking. But, the truth starts here.
A little girl named Bella is watching the TV, and it was talking about air pollution. Bella said to her pet dog Doggy “This is a very big problem to our Earth. We have to do something.”
A voice from behind says “What are you doing?? It is already 10 o’clock?? You have class tomorrow. Today is Monday.</description></item><item><title>Save the World</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/save-the-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/save-the-world/</guid><description>Age 7
I am a cat sleeping in the warm sunlight, enjoying the breeze. Boom! I hear the sound of bombs. Boom! Boom! I run and run until I see the most horrible sight anyone has ever seen.
There are tanks, military helicopters and soldiers holding guns.
I suddenly feel someone pick me up. I look up to see a young girl. She takes me into her arms and runs as fast as she can.</description></item><item><title>Save the World</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/save-the-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/save-the-world/</guid><description>It all started when the world was filled with fumes and stuff like that. Until it was dawn that day… Do you know what happened? It all turned into candy. But luckily there were no more fumes! Instead of fumes there was candy floss. And surprisingly, when someone went to a tree they saw a rainbow straw and he drank from it and it was very sweet. But when he got home he grew fat!</description></item><item><title>Seaweed</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/seaweed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/seaweed/</guid><description>The dark eye of the whale focused contemplatively on the thick clumps of seaweed streaming past. The fronds brushed up against her skin, which like her eye, took in the colour and shape of the fresh green plants. Blinking slowly, she rolled towards the surface, pulled a deep gasp of empty air into her lungs, turned her fins, and directed the movement and power of her body downwards.
Below in the depths, her family circled, noses touching tails, grandmothers of hundreds of years covered in thousands of barnacles brushing up against last year’s babies, smooth as silk and bright pale grey.</description></item><item><title>Seaweed</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/seaweed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/seaweed/</guid><description>The dark eye of the whale focused contemplatively on the thick clumps of seaweed streaming past. The fronds brushed up against her skin, which like her eye, took in the colour and shape of the fresh green plants. Blinking slowly, she rolled towards the surface, pulled a deep gasp of empty air into her lungs, turned her fins, and directed the movement and power of her body downwards.
Below in the depths, her family circled, noses touching tails, grandmothers of hundreds of years covered in thousands of barnacles brushing up against last year’s babies, smooth as silk and bright pale grey.</description></item><item><title>Shell</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/shell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/shell/</guid><description>“Come back here!”
The man waved to a little boy running to the beach behind a group of older kids. The child ignored him. The man shrugged, after days of rain there was no keeping the kids still. He walked back in and the door closed behind him.
The kids&amp;rsquo; laughter was still within earshot, the sun in his face, and the old man extended his legs. The golden light was filling the courtyard but through his worn-out jeans, he could feel the cold stone he was sitting on.</description></item><item><title>Signs of Change</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/19+/signs-of-change/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/19+/signs-of-change/</guid><description>God, my feet hurt. It’s not just the half-mile walk to this hippie pavilion, or the fact that I’m technically obese, according to my doctor, who based this medical pronouncement on a bogus formula dreamed up by some fucking mathematician from Belgium. No, the real reason my feet hurt is because I’ve got nothing but an ancient pair of sandals to walk around in. My last honest pair of tennis shoes I gave to some kid who, from the looks of his bare and busted feet would’ve paid his last dollar for even my crummy sandals.</description></item><item><title>Sooty</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/sooty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/sooty/</guid><description>If there was one word to describe the city it was small. Tiny compared to the Fuel Era cities. Or at least the ruins of them. In the centre were the towers and the bigger buildings, not too dissimilar to the old cities. Just smaller. Every building had either a wind turbine on it or tracking solar array. When viewed from a distance it looked like a collection of potted flowers.</description></item><item><title>Sooty</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/sooty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/sooty/</guid><description>If there was one word to describe the city it was small. Tiny compared to the Fuel Era cities. Or at least the ruins of them. In the centre were the towers and the bigger buildings, not too dissimilar to the old cities. Just smaller. Every building had either a wind turbine on it or tracking solar array. When viewed from a distance it looked like a collection of potted flowers.</description></item><item><title>StoriesHome</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories-home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories-home/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Take Care of Earth</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/take-care-of-earth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/take-care-of-earth/</guid><description>Age 7
Once upon a time, I saw a man using an ax to cut down trees. It made me feel sad. I yelled, “Don’t use that ax! Cutting down trees will destroy the forest.”
The man said “okay, I’ll stop.”
Then I saw that there were some flowers dying. They didn’t have water. So, I used some water and poured it on the flower. I also planted some more flowers and trees.</description></item><item><title>Taking Care of Endangered Leopards</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/taking-care-of-endangered-leopards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/taking-care-of-endangered-leopards/</guid><description>Age 10
One day, as I am walking by a farm, I see a very big and beautiful grassland. There are more than 63,833 chickens. So I can go to the farm and eat chicken everyday for breakfast. Today, I am doing the same thing as every day when I wake up. I am very hungry, so I jump into the farm and eat the chickens. It tastes so yummy and good!</description></item><item><title>The Awakening</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/the-awakening/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/the-awakening/</guid><description>Bran
I rise before dawn, the moon still bright enough to light the way. The air is cool as I breathe in the scents borne on the breeze. Sweet pine resin, one of the substances I am here to collect, along with meadowsweet, fennel and lavender, the herbs required by the healer. Some are hardy and easy to find, thriving in the open. Others hide in the shadows, growing near the stream, shielded from the heat of the coming day by the overhanging canopy.</description></item><item><title>The Beach Clean Up</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-beach-clean-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-beach-clean-up/</guid><description>Age 8
One day, my mom tells me a story about a beach covered in trash. I started to think about it and thought maybe there are some people who aren’t very nice. I think I need to help clean the beach.
My mom says, “You can go pick up trash at the beach.”
I thought that was a good idea. I told my mom that I would good tomorrow since I didn’t have class that day.</description></item><item><title>The Black Forest</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-black-forest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-black-forest/</guid><description>Age 10
Nowadays, we see a lot of people polluting the environment. The environmental problem has become bigger and bigger. The plastic problem is also a big problem for the environment. Now, I am going to tell you an environmental story.
A long, long time ago, there was a girl called Mini, and Mini liked to play around in the forest. One day, Mini was playing with her friend, Lili. They were both born in the same year on the same day, so many people called them twins.</description></item><item><title>The First Stone</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-first-stone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-first-stone/</guid><description>Tessa was playing at the edge of the boundary line when she first stumbled upon it. Hundreds of polished stones arranged into interconnecting circles at a flat clearing on the hilltop. Against the chestnut and walnut tree bark, it looked as though it was floating. A chilly breeze stirred up the leaves and whirled around her.
Her uncle had told her not to go there.
‘Don’t touch it,’ Tessa could hear his warning voice in her mind.</description></item><item><title>The Future School</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/future-school/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/future-school/</guid><description>Nowadays, students do not enjoy school much because it is boring. So a lot of teachers are determined to make the school a fun place, while keeping it safe and eco-friendly. But how? We’ll find out!
Outside there will be an invisible protection zone, when you want to go to the school there will be fingerprint recognition to check if it is you, also there will be a hand sanitizer inside.</description></item><item><title>The Future School</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/future-school/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/future-school/</guid><description>Nowadays, students do not enjoy school much because it is boring. So a lot of teachers are determined to make the school a fun place, while keeping it safe and eco-friendly. But how? We’ll find out!
Outside there will be an invisible protection zone, when you want to go to the school there will be fingerprint recognition to check if it is you, also there will be a hand sanitizer inside.</description></item><item><title>The Gift to Earth</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-gift-to-earth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-gift-to-earth/</guid><description>Age 9
One day, there was a young boy. He said, “I want to give the Earth a gift.” He thought about what he could give the Earth and then he decided to build 100 parks. His parks had colorful flowers and trees. The air was good. The boy was happy with his gift to Earth, even the animals had a good home.
The Earth is our friend. We need parks and animals to live in it.</description></item><item><title>The Happy Wolf</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/happy-wolf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/happy-wolf/</guid><description>My name is Axel. I like being a wolf because I have a lovely forest with Evergreen trees. Like Christmas trees. And it is very cold because I am in the Arctic. I like the Evergreen trees because they keep us healthy.
Now that we’re not being hunted we get to run around and be more safe. The snow is thick and white and it feels rough. We get to play games.</description></item><item><title>The Happy Wolf</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/happy-wolf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/happy-wolf/</guid><description>My name is Axel. I like being a wolf because I have a lovely forest with Evergreen trees. Like Christmas trees. And it is very cold because I am in the Arctic. I like the Evergreen trees because they keep us healthy.
Now that we’re not being hunted we get to run around and be more safe. The snow is thick and white and it feels rough. We get to play games.</description></item><item><title>The Kids Who Made a Future</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/11-and-under/the-kids-who-made-a-future/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/11-and-under/the-kids-who-made-a-future/</guid><description>Once upon a time there was a girl who loved nature. But she could see that our world was in danger. That little girl was Phoebe. Her best friend Arianne also wanted to help the environment. One day they were sitting on the sofa thinking of ideas for what to plant in the garden, when Arianne had the best idea ever! “Phoebe, this is nothing to do with planting but what if we made a time machine to see how good or bad the pollution is?</description></item><item><title>The Last Vaquitas</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-last-vaquitas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-last-vaquitas/</guid><description>Age 10
I’m swimming in the deep, blue ocean. I feel alone because I haven’t seen any other vaquitas for a very long time. All of this is because of illegal fishing. The fishermen keep fishing us and we are almost extinct now. There are only around 10 of us left in the world! This is also because of the pollution and spread of diseases. Just like right now, I see a ton of trash right in front of me.</description></item><item><title>The Librarian</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/the-librarian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/the-librarian/</guid><description>Thirty Days After Midsummer Seventeen Years after the Great Unmaking I wake with the song of birds. As a child in my mothers house. Silence. No cars, no trucks on the road outside.
There is the silence and the singing of the birds. It must be Sunday. No school. Sleep confuses me. I remember, with a shock. There is no school. There are no schools. They have gone. I am not a child, the dreams are slipping away.</description></item><item><title>The Light and Shadow of the Forest</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/11-and-under/the-light-and-shadow-of-the-forest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/11-and-under/the-light-and-shadow-of-the-forest/</guid><description>A blonde girl with a white dress walked through the forest, calling out to her parents, wishing they could hear her cries. Her name was Lily. She walked deeper and deeper into the dark forest. The trees all looked the same, with the same haunting era. She scrunched up her nose in disgust as she saw a fox, killed by a misplaced trap. She left it and kept walking. Tiny squeals sounded from a nearby withered bramble bush, she peeked in and saw a family of rabbits curling up around one another, the sight warmed her heart.</description></item><item><title>The Lost Chapter</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/12-18/the-lost-chapter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/12-18/the-lost-chapter/</guid><description>It was a rainy December afternoon on Cornelia Street. I walked into a small antique bookstore, the smell of dusty untouched books filled the air. My muddy shoes tracked across the vintage carpet as I silently strolled down the long corridor, admiring the stunning architecture and dark wooden bookshelves around me. The elegance of the bookstore enchanted me, and slowly, I wandered to the basement. It was as though time had stopped.</description></item><item><title>The Lost Home</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-lost-home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-lost-home/</guid><description>Age 8
My home was once beautiful. But now, it’s full of trash. I still look up and see the sun shining bright orange and red across the beautiful sea. I am a little crab and this is where I live.
I always need to find a new home. I don’t feel comfortable and there aren’t many choices. I once lived in a plastic cup for a little while. I didn’t really like it there.</description></item><item><title>The Moon Doth Shine As Bright As Day</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/19+/the-moon-doth-shine-as-bright-as-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/19+/the-moon-doth-shine-as-bright-as-day/</guid><description>Joseph had never liked being called the school Premises Manager. He knew the title was meant to confer a certain authority on him, but he much preferred the old word – caretaker. He took care. He’d pay attention to that odd plaintive whistle from a radiator, a sign that a bleed that was due. He’d see the blotch of mould in the corner of the boys’ toilets, note the chipped hand basin with a sharp edge.</description></item><item><title>The Old Man and the Bird</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/old-man-bird/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/old-man-bird/</guid><description>It had been years since the bird heard the last trucks, saws, and men cutting down the trees, killing its friends, and destroying its home. The colorful bird was singing on its tree, waiting for the Old Man to tell him stories. The Old Man told him about men’s cities: lush forests of blue, green, and gold, far away from the bird’s home. The stories were so different from the tales of the bird’s grandfather, who told him about dark, grey places of fear and misery.</description></item><item><title>The Old Man and the Bird</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/old-man-bird/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/old-man-bird/</guid><description>It had been years since the bird heard the last trucks, saws, and men cutting down the trees, killing its friends, and destroying its home. The colorful bird was singing on its tree, waiting for the Old Man to tell him stories. The Old Man told him about men’s cities: lush forests of blue, green, and gold, far away from the bird’s home. The stories were so different from the tales of the bird’s grandfather, who told him about dark, grey places of fear and misery.</description></item><item><title>The Parallel Lives of Clara McDonald</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/the-parallel-lives-of-clara-mcdonald/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/the-parallel-lives-of-clara-mcdonald/</guid><description>You can call me Sol and think of me as a healer with a patient with a raging fever. In reality, I’m a pan-dimensional entity tasked with making a handful of universes flourish, and one of them is seriously ill. Every universe, you see, splits into two once in a while, a bit like how your cells divide. It doesn’t happen often, because universe membranes are robust. They have to be.</description></item><item><title>The Park</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/the-park/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/the-park/</guid><description>The child’s face was cold, with a coating of frost and an icicle hanging off the end of her chin.
The sun glinted off her forehead in fits and starts as it peeked through the clouds, but it was too little to warm her.
It was January, after all, and it had been a cloudy winter.
Jules always cut through the park on her way to work, but she liked it best this time of year.</description></item><item><title>The Park</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/the-park/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/the-park/</guid><description>The child’s face was cold, with a coating of frost and an icicle hanging off the end of her chin.
The sun glinted off her forehead in fits and starts as it peeked through the clouds, but it was too little to warm her.
It was January, after all, and it had been a cloudy winter.
Jules always cut through the park on her way to work, but she liked it best this time of year.</description></item><item><title>The Poor Butterfly</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-poor-butterfly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-poor-butterfly/</guid><description>Age 7
If you were a bug, you would have a very sad life because some people kill bugs to make imprints. Some people catch bugs to bring them home. So, bugs are in danger and we need to protect them.
There was once the most beautiful butterfly living happily by herself, enjoying the pretty flowers. One day, a man caught her and took her home. He wanted to keep her in a jar and watch her every day.</description></item><item><title>The Singer of Seeds</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/singer-of-seeds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/singer-of-seeds/</guid><description>Maïa climbs up the ladder and tries to sit next to me with as little noise as possible.
“You’re late,” I mutter, and it comes out more annoyed than I am.
“I know,” she whispers, crossing her legs on the sandwood boards to my mat, as she has forgotten hers again.
We stare at the landscape before us, a hand risen up to our faces, covering the left eye. Our right eye is fixed on that jagged line of mountain crests on the horizon, where the purple haze is shifting into a warm peach light.</description></item><item><title>The Singer of Seeds</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/singer-of-seeds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/singer-of-seeds/</guid><description>Maïa climbs up the ladder and tries to sit next to me with as little noise as possible.
“You’re late,” I mutter, and it comes out more annoyed than I am.
“I know,” she whispers, crossing her legs on the sandwood boards to my mat, as she has forgotten hers again.
We stare at the landscape before us, a hand risen up to our faces, covering the left eye. Our right eye is fixed on that jagged line of mountain crests on the horizon, where the purple haze is shifting into a warm peach light.</description></item><item><title>The Spirit of Christmas Future</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/11-and-under/the-spirit-of-christmas-future/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/11-and-under/the-spirit-of-christmas-future/</guid><description>Have you ever had spooky spirits haunting your dreams at night? Well you’re in for a rough ride if you haven’t. Fasten your seatbelt and hold on tight because your nightmares are about to come to life!
A young female teenager goes to sleep angrily on December 23rd. She tells her pet dog, “I don’t even want to celebrate Christmas this year.” Let’s rewind for a second. The girl, Eliana sits at the round dinner table and glares at her phone nonstop.</description></item><item><title>The Talking Trash Cans</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-talking-trash-cans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-talking-trash-cans/</guid><description>Age 6
The trash cans are everywhere. They can talk and eat paper. Some trash cans can even eat plastic. They also teach us lessons. The trash cans say, “Don’t throw trash on the floor, please! Throw trash in the trash cans!”
The trash cans tell us their job is to keep the Earth clean. At night, the trash cans don’t sleep and the trash cans talk to people about not throwing trash on the floor.</description></item><item><title>The Tides Rolled In</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/tides-rolled/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/tides-rolled/</guid><description>The tides rolled in. The tides rolled out. It was as simple as that. And in that simplicity there was power. Enough to light entire cities, even, not that Afton knew personally. Her little village did just fine, roaming the waves, but in her thirteen years she’d never seen the capital of the Floating Republic. She’d never walked on sidewalks so steady it was said you couldn’t even feel the rocking of the waves.</description></item><item><title>The Tides Rolled In</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/tides-rolled/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/tides-rolled/</guid><description>The tides rolled in. The tides rolled out. It was as simple as that. And in that simplicity there was power. Enough to light entire cities, even, not that Afton knew personally. Her little village did just fine, roaming the waves, but in her thirteen years she’d never seen the capital of the Floating Republic. She’d never walked on sidewalks so steady it was said you couldn’t even feel the rocking of the waves.</description></item><item><title>The Trash Cans</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-trash-cans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/the-trash-cans/</guid><description>Age 7
I see trash cans flying in the sky. They can walk, laugh and collect trash in the air. They can turn into very small bins. They can eat plastic, paper, cans, shoes and books.
The trash cans can fly very fast. If they eat crayons, they will be very angry. They don’t like crayons! If they eat erasers, they eat erasers, they will be very happy. They like erasers!</description></item><item><title>The Well-Trodden Path</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/well-trodden/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/well-trodden/</guid><description>“Where are they?” asked Blue, transferring into the cockpit. “How worried are we?” “They’re post-nuclear, pre-Universal,” replied Grey, projecting a zoomed-in view of the industrial complexes which studded the blue/beige planet they were orbiting. Blue performed the guttural vibrations which in their culture meant frustration, and complained: “Just once, I’d like to find a people we can talk with who don’t yet have the means and inclination to incinerate everything.”</description></item><item><title>The Well-Trodden Path</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/well-trodden/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/well-trodden/</guid><description>“Where are they?” asked Blue, transferring into the cockpit. “How worried are we?” “They’re post-nuclear, pre-Universal,” replied Grey, projecting a zoomed-in view of the industrial complexes which studded the blue/beige planet they were orbiting. Blue performed the guttural vibrations which in their culture meant frustration, and complained: “Just once, I’d like to find a people we can talk with who don’t yet have the means and inclination to incinerate everything.”</description></item><item><title>The Wompom Forest</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/19+/the-wompom-forest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/19+/the-wompom-forest/</guid><description>Burt was not a bad person; he just took his job as Chief Guardian of the Wompom Forest very seriously. The Wompom Tree was quite simply the most useful and valuable thing in the world. The entire community depended on it for everything, because quite simply, there was nothing a Wompom could not do.
The many coloured fruits of the Wompom fulfilled all dietary needs. It was important to get a variety and everyone was reminded to “Get your five colours a day”.</description></item><item><title>Tomorrow's Greatest Mystery</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/12-18/tomorrows-greatest-mystery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/12-18/tomorrows-greatest-mystery/</guid><description>The night was warm, and Tim could hear cicadas singing in the distance. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s time to wake up.&amp;rdquo; he thought.
Tim&amp;rsquo;s bed, mostly made from mycelium and wood fibers. It was comfy, and getting up in the morning was one of the hardest things he had to do every day. It was his privilege. The sun&amp;rsquo;s warm light finally went through Tim&amp;rsquo;s windows as he got up. &amp;ldquo;Here we go again&amp;rdquo; he whispered to himself, cracking a smile.</description></item><item><title>Utopia in the Sewers</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/utopia-sewers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/utopia-sewers/</guid><description>September 28th, Daylight. They have overtaken the surface for quite some time now. Their calendars say the year is 2089, ours 58. I do not know which one’s true. We are safe underground in a place the surface people call Esenyurt. They don’t come down, we don’t go up. Sewers run deep. They don’t allow us at the surface of the city. They send their nuclear waste and garbage down here.</description></item><item><title>Utopia in the Sewers</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/utopia-sewers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/utopia-sewers/</guid><description>September 28th, Daylight. They have overtaken the surface for quite some time now. Their calendars say the year is 2089, ours 58. I do not know which one’s true. We are safe underground in a place the surface people call Esenyurt. They don’t come down, we don’t go up. Sewers run deep. They don’t allow us at the surface of the city. They send their nuclear waste and garbage down here.</description></item><item><title>Wake Up Call</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/wake-up-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/wake-up-call/</guid><description>07:05 hours, on the 5th March, in the year 2123.
Kai McIntyre woke from a dream in which he was flying over a vast and ancient jungle. A little disheartened as reality dawned on him that the being-able-to-fly bit was only a dream, he opened the curtains to gaze lovingly across the treetops of the temperate forest city that was, thankfully in reality, his home. This was his favourite dream and, as it happens, his favourite view of Edinburgh as well.</description></item><item><title>Wall of Flowers</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/wall-flowers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/wall-flowers/</guid><description>Never do this. I&amp;rsquo;m not the most outdoorsy person, but even I know that if you&amp;rsquo;re lost and alone in the woods, it&amp;rsquo;s a bad idea to scoff a bunch of unidentified mushrooms. The thing is, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t help myself. The afternoon sun slanting through the trees was so golden, the colours of the autumn leaves so alluring, that I had wandered further and further from the trail; and when I came to a clearing filled with shifting, dappled light and saw the clump of small, pale blue mushrooms gleaming like strange gemstones, it seemed the most natural thing in the world to nibble one.</description></item><item><title>Wall of Flowers</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/wall-flowers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/wall-flowers/</guid><description>Never do this. I&amp;rsquo;m not the most outdoorsy person, but even I know that if you&amp;rsquo;re lost and alone in the woods, it&amp;rsquo;s a bad idea to scoff a bunch of unidentified mushrooms. The thing is, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t help myself. The afternoon sun slanting through the trees was so golden, the colours of the autumn leaves so alluring, that I had wandered further and further from the trail; and when I came to a clearing filled with shifting, dappled light and saw the clump of small, pale blue mushrooms gleaming like strange gemstones, it seemed the most natural thing in the world to nibble one.</description></item><item><title>Where Giants Will Stand</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/giants-stand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/giants-stand/</guid><description>Cora and Rosa caught me in the garden. They rode their bikes under the arched passion fruit vines and into our driveway. I had just finished pruning the tomatoes. Knees achy, I welcomed their timing.
“Hi Grandpa!” Rosa yelled as she raced past the olive guild and the perfumed loquats.
“Happy birthday, my sweet child!”
She laid her bike down, hopped a garden bed and smothered me.
“Your grandpop and I made you a present,” I whispered conspiratorially in her ear.</description></item><item><title>Where Giants Will Stand</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/giants-stand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/giants-stand/</guid><description>Cora and Rosa caught me in the garden. They rode their bikes under the arched passion fruit vines and into our driveway. I had just finished pruning the tomatoes. Knees achy, I welcomed their timing.
“Hi Grandpa!” Rosa yelled as she raced past the olive guild and the perfumed loquats.
“Happy birthday, my sweet child!”
She laid her bike down, hopped a garden bed and smothered me.
“Your grandpop and I made you a present,” I whispered conspiratorially in her ear.</description></item><item><title>WINNERS 11 &amp; Under</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/11-and-under/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/11-and-under/</guid><description>The Happy Wolf by Mikhayel, age 6. London, England
Dylan Cooler
by Dylan, age 9. Taipei, Taiwan
The Future School by Liz, age 10. Taipei, Taiwan</description></item><item><title>WINNERS 12 - 18</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/12-18-winners/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/12-18-winners/</guid><description>City Starlight &amp; The Cemetery
by Katrina Eilender. New Jersey, U.S.A.
The Old Man and the Bird by Aël Magnard. Paris, France.
Blood Oil
by Rebecca "Reb" Spring. Washington DC, U.S.A</description></item><item><title>WINNERS 19 &amp; Over</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/18-ov-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/18-ov-1/</guid><description>Gabby's First Kiss
by Joe Tankersley. Florida, U.S.A. Where Giants Will Stand
by Spencer R. Scott. California, U.S.A
The Tides Rolled In
by Chris Muscato. Colorado, U.S.A.</description></item><item><title>Wolves in Yellowstone</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/wolves-in-yellowstone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/honorable-mentions/wolves-in-yellowstone/</guid><description>Age 9
Today I see many people holding a sign that reads Wolves don’t belong in Yellowstone.
“What are you doing?” I ask. “Wolves are good!”
The man holding the sign put it down. “Wolves are not good! They kill ranchers and farmers’ livestock. If we don’t kick the wolves out of Yellowstone, we won’t have any meat to eat!”
I was so shocked. I felt that I needed to save the wolves in Yellowstone.</description></item><item><title>XR Wordsmiths' Top Picks</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/xr-top-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/xr-top-1/</guid><description>The Singer of Seeds
by Leda Baöl. Torino, Italy / Amsterdam, The Netherlands.
The Park
by Adam Marx. Borehamwood, England.</description></item></channel></rss>