<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Runners Up on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/runners-up/</link><description>Recent content in Runners Up on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/runners-up/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lichenicolous</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/runners-up/lichenicolous/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/runners-up/lichenicolous/</guid><description>“Estimated high UV later in the week.” Eloise frowned slightly and glanced up. “I think we ought to up-regulate.” She crossed the room to the lichen interface and tapped on the screen.
Tasneem looked up. “Auto not recommending?”
“Mmm. No. But it’s been reasonably high anyway, and last time there was a high few days the photobiont suffered.”
“Okay, I trust you, if you think it’s best.”
Eloise programmed in increased UV protection and pressed send.</description></item><item><title>Mily's Adventure of Future Houses</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/runners-up/milys-adventure-of-future-houses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/runners-up/milys-adventure-of-future-houses/</guid><description>Once there was a girl called Mily. She was a very kind child; she cared about the Earth a lot. She knew that the earth was turning warm because people kept cutting down trees and there will be no trees to give us clean oxygen.
One day, when she was walking on the street, she saw a small, weird creature passing through her and left a pretty gazing ball in front of her.</description></item><item><title>Mr. Smith’s Unpleasant Last Day</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/runners-up/mr-smiths-unpleasant-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/runners-up/mr-smiths-unpleasant-day/</guid><description>“Shit!” Aldous Smith always took care walking through his neighborhood’s allotment. The tall grass and wildflower patches made the long trek to his Ford Fiesta a ‘perilous’ journey - in his mind. He always took care when plodding through the grass. But this time Aldous stepped right in it.
‘Probably a fox’, he thought ‘checking on the honeycombs.’
25 years ago, this space was a parking lot. It was only a three minute walk from Aldous’s front door to his car.</description></item><item><title>Of Creatures &amp; Caretakers</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/runners-up/of-creatures-and-caretakers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/runners-up/of-creatures-and-caretakers/</guid><description>Network whisperings are delighting her soul. She reaches out to her kin and exchanges sustenance through the embrace of wide-reaching arms. A new bloom is mutually shared, and layers of soil are teeming with life, infinitely invigorating.
“We are growing,” they whisper, taking her many hands to guide her. She feels the pinpricks of smaller meshwork connecting with her own. There, supported by many loving arms a new born oak sapling pokes its head through the soil, moist with morning dew.</description></item></channel></rss>