<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>XR Picks on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/</link><description>Recent content in XR Picks on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Save the World</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/save-the-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/save-the-world/</guid><description>It all started when the world was filled with fumes and stuff like that. Until it was dawn that day… Do you know what happened? It all turned into candy. But luckily there were no more fumes! Instead of fumes there was candy floss. And surprisingly, when someone went to a tree they saw a rainbow straw and he drank from it and it was very sweet. But when he got home he grew fat!</description></item><item><title>The Awakening</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/the-awakening/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/the-awakening/</guid><description>Bran
I rise before dawn, the moon still bright enough to light the way. The air is cool as I breathe in the scents borne on the breeze. Sweet pine resin, one of the substances I am here to collect, along with meadowsweet, fennel and lavender, the herbs required by the healer. Some are hardy and easy to find, thriving in the open. Others hide in the shadows, growing near the stream, shielded from the heat of the coming day by the overhanging canopy.</description></item><item><title>The Librarian</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/the-librarian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/the-librarian/</guid><description>Thirty Days After Midsummer Seventeen Years after the Great Unmaking I wake with the song of birds. As a child in my mothers house. Silence. No cars, no trucks on the road outside.
There is the silence and the singing of the birds. It must be Sunday. No school. Sleep confuses me. I remember, with a shock. There is no school. There are no schools. They have gone. I am not a child, the dreams are slipping away.</description></item><item><title>The Parallel Lives of Clara McDonald</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/the-parallel-lives-of-clara-mcdonald/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/the-parallel-lives-of-clara-mcdonald/</guid><description>You can call me Sol and think of me as a healer with a patient with a raging fever. In reality, I’m a pan-dimensional entity tasked with making a handful of universes flourish, and one of them is seriously ill. Every universe, you see, splits into two once in a while, a bit like how your cells divide. It doesn’t happen often, because universe membranes are robust. They have to be.</description></item><item><title>Wake Up Call</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/wake-up-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/xr-picks/wake-up-call/</guid><description>07:05 hours, on the 5th March, in the year 2123.
Kai McIntyre woke from a dream in which he was flying over a vast and ancient jungle. A little disheartened as reality dawned on him that the being-able-to-fly bit was only a dream, he opened the curtains to gaze lovingly across the treetops of the temperate forest city that was, thankfully in reality, his home. This was his favourite dream and, as it happens, his favourite view of Edinburgh as well.</description></item></channel></rss>