<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>19+ on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2021/stories/19+/</link><description>Recent content in 19+ on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2021/stories/19+/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gabby's First Kiss</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/gabby/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/gabby/</guid><description>Gabby nearly knocked her mother over as she rushed through the kitchen and out the front door. Outside, she paused to look over the horizon. Her home, like all the homes in Bahía del Paraíso, sat high in the air; protected from the floods that were a regular part of life in their small coastal community. From her perch, she could easily see all the way to the bay. In the early morning sunlight, the mangroves along the water’s edge glowed as if they were on fire.</description></item><item><title>The Tides Rolled In</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/tides-rolled/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/tides-rolled/</guid><description>The tides rolled in. The tides rolled out. It was as simple as that. And in that simplicity there was power. Enough to light entire cities, even, not that Afton knew personally. Her little village did just fine, roaming the waves, but in her thirteen years she’d never seen the capital of the Floating Republic. She’d never walked on sidewalks so steady it was said you couldn’t even feel the rocking of the waves.</description></item><item><title>Where Giants Will Stand</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/giants-stand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/giants-stand/</guid><description>Cora and Rosa caught me in the garden. They rode their bikes under the arched passion fruit vines and into our driveway. I had just finished pruning the tomatoes. Knees achy, I welcomed their timing.
“Hi Grandpa!” Rosa yelled as she raced past the olive guild and the perfumed loquats.
“Happy birthday, my sweet child!”
She laid her bike down, hopped a garden bed and smothered me.
“Your grandpop and I made you a present,” I whispered conspiratorially in her ear.</description></item></channel></rss>