<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Penned by the Wordsmiths on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/penned-by-the-wordsmiths/</link><description>Recent content in Penned by the Wordsmiths on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/penned-by-the-wordsmiths/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>50 Shades of Green</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/penned-by-the-wordsmiths/50-shades-of-green/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/penned-by-the-wordsmiths/50-shades-of-green/</guid><description>Castor looked around him at the wilderness he was helping to rebuild. There was a long way to go - but it was starting to look better. What had been a barren wasteland with a stagnant lake fed by a miserable network of anorexic streams was slowly blossoming into green wilderness. Indeed, the rewilding project had got to the point where further species were being reintroduced. Among the first species reintroduced was the beaver, and this was where he came in.</description></item><item><title>Amal</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/penned-by-the-wordsmiths/amal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/penned-by-the-wordsmiths/amal/</guid><description>She stretched her right leg out before her, gingerly dipping her big toe into the water. The first touch was cool, making her gasp and giggle in surprise, but it quickly melted into a warm welcome from the marsh water. She lowered her foot in further, throwing her arms wide and grasping a clump of reeds to balance— ever careful not to drop one precious date from her colorful reed-woven basket.</description></item><item><title>Colouring In</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/penned-by-the-wordsmiths/colouring-in/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/penned-by-the-wordsmiths/colouring-in/</guid><description>“I think you’re a pink,” said Leaf with a smile. The boy glanced at her and looked away towards the window. She watched him for another few seconds. “I’ll change the leaves on your dressing in a bit,” she said. “You’ll soon be back swinging from branch to branch, like a gorilla.” She beat her chest lightly and gave a few little howls. The boy looked round at her. “That’s wolf,” he said.</description></item></channel></rss>