<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Artwork on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/artwork/</link><description>Recent content in The Artwork on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/artwork/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mori</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/artwork/mori/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/artwork/mori/</guid><description>Mori is a digital artist from a small city in Chile. After studying Illustration and Graphic Design in DuocUC, she’s worked on several freelance projects: drawing characters for TV animations, illustrations for books and websites, t-shirt designs, prints, and posters. She’s also collaborated with several artists and participated in local Illustration fairs. Nowadays she is focused on creating new merch with the Dream.Mori signature. Mori is inspired by dreams, the unconscious and intrusive thoughts, which she combines to create evocative sensations through a digital canvas.</description></item><item><title>Rita Fei</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/artwork/rita-fei/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/artwork/rita-fei/</guid><description>Rita Fei is an illustrator based in Vancouver, BC, and who graduated from Emily Carr University of Art and Design. She loves creating characters and worlds for the wonderfully broad spectrum of speculative fiction, and had a piece published in Spectrum 26. She is currently working full-time as a designer at Bardel Entertainment, and occasionally as a freelancer for various projects. Her entry for the Solarpunk Atomhawk competition was chosen as the title image for this Showcase.</description></item></channel></rss>