<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>19+ on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/19+/</link><description>Recent content in 19+ on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/19+/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adder’s Crystal</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/19+/adders-crystal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/19+/adders-crystal/</guid><description>Adder stared quizzically at the dried and brittle thing in her line of vision, which had been a flower only three months before. A cold northern wind blew the delicate husk of its stem from side to side like an old disjointed fence post caught in a tornado.
A great mass rose from over the horizon. Lifted by a force as incomprehensible to Adder as the changing of the seasons, it charged into the open sky and disappeared.</description></item><item><title>Signs of Change</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/19+/signs-of-change/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/19+/signs-of-change/</guid><description>God, my feet hurt. It’s not just the half-mile walk to this hippie pavilion, or the fact that I’m technically obese, according to my doctor, who based this medical pronouncement on a bogus formula dreamed up by some fucking mathematician from Belgium. No, the real reason my feet hurt is because I’ve got nothing but an ancient pair of sandals to walk around in. My last honest pair of tennis shoes I gave to some kid who, from the looks of his bare and busted feet would’ve paid his last dollar for even my crummy sandals.</description></item><item><title>The Moon Doth Shine As Bright As Day</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/19+/the-moon-doth-shine-as-bright-as-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/19+/the-moon-doth-shine-as-bright-as-day/</guid><description>Joseph had never liked being called the school Premises Manager. He knew the title was meant to confer a certain authority on him, but he much preferred the old word – caretaker. He took care. He’d pay attention to that odd plaintive whistle from a radiator, a sign that a bleed that was due. He’d see the blotch of mould in the corner of the boys’ toilets, note the chipped hand basin with a sharp edge.</description></item><item><title>The Wompom Forest</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/19+/the-wompom-forest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/19+/the-wompom-forest/</guid><description>Burt was not a bad person; he just took his job as Chief Guardian of the Wompom Forest very seriously. The Wompom Tree was quite simply the most useful and valuable thing in the world. The entire community depended on it for everything, because quite simply, there was nothing a Wompom could not do.
The many coloured fruits of the Wompom fulfilled all dietary needs. It was important to get a variety and everyone was reminded to “Get your five colours a day”.</description></item></channel></rss>