<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Runners Up on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2021/stories/runners-up/</link><description>Recent content in Runners Up on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2021/stories/runners-up/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automata Albatross</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/automata-albatross/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/automata-albatross/</guid><description>The albatross almost struck Akila as it fell. With a metallic shriek, it plummeted from the empty gray sky to shatter at her feet, wires spilling onto the slick cement of the sidewalk. She stood frozen in shock as tendrils of steam coolant curled through her braids, its beak chattering eerily as it shuddered into stillness. A dead albatross was very bad luck, her offshore studies professor had told her. Perhaps he would know what to do with it.</description></item><item><title>Green Witch</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/green-witch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/green-witch/</guid><description>Between sunset and starlight spans the twilight, and that is when we witches gather to dance in the garden. Live by the sun, love by the moon, so goes the old saying. A catchy soundbite, a t-shirt slogan, but truer now than ever before, as the solar panels swallow greedily the last peach-red-golden rays on the horizon, as the city sighs its relief and prepares to settle into slumber. The suburbs come alive with a patchwork of lights.</description></item><item><title>Hospitalized in Utopia</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/hospitalized-utopia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/hospitalized-utopia/</guid><description>Diana looked out the window at the sky. It was a good sky, she liked looking at it, but she couldn’t look at much else. If she turned her head the other way she could see only pale blue walls, medical equipment, and a glimpse of that machine in the hallway that went beep! beep! beep! She couldn’t imagine what it did—and she had tried.
Supposedly her window actually had a lovely view of half the green city.</description></item><item><title>Return to Kiribati</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/return-kiribati/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/return-kiribati/</guid><description>Only the cold, untwinkling speck of a space station pierced the darkness between the thinning cumulus and the churning ink-black sea.
The storm sail billowed and creaked, water thundered like rapids between the three hulls, and Kraken hydrofoiled a metre clear of the water, slicing through the detritus of coconuts and disintegrating plastic that had been whipped into a seething broth by the Pacific cyclone wind. My eyes combed the ebony veils of rain for signs of pursuit, but the outcasts’ ramshackle vessel couldn’t have made it through.</description></item><item><title>Wall of Flowers</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/wall-flowers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/wall-flowers/</guid><description>Never do this. I&amp;rsquo;m not the most outdoorsy person, but even I know that if you&amp;rsquo;re lost and alone in the woods, it&amp;rsquo;s a bad idea to scoff a bunch of unidentified mushrooms. The thing is, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t help myself. The afternoon sun slanting through the trees was so golden, the colours of the autumn leaves so alluring, that I had wandered further and further from the trail; and when I came to a clearing filled with shifting, dappled light and saw the clump of small, pale blue mushrooms gleaming like strange gemstones, it seemed the most natural thing in the world to nibble one.</description></item></channel></rss>