<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2023-showcases on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023-showcase/</link><description>Recent content in 2023-showcases on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023-showcase/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023-showcase/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023-showcase/overview/</guid><description>The 2023 XR Solarpunk Showcase is now open for entries! In 2021, Extinction Rebellion launched its first ever Solarpunk Showcase; a global fiction writing competition organised by XR Wordsmiths. We had such an incredible response that we are organising another one. And so without further ado, we announce that the 2023 XR Solarpunk Showcase is live and ready for your entries!
Once again, we want to use our collective imagination as a tool against the climate and ecological emergency.</description></item><item><title>2023 Showcase FAQ</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023-showcase/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023-showcase/faq/</guid><description>Q: Who are XR Wordsmiths?
A: We are a band/collective of writers who are deeply concerned with the climate and ecological emergency facing us all. We are a part of Extinction Rebellion, and hail from all over the world. Our writing is one way we battle against this emergency — we hope it spurs curiosity, concern, inspiration, reflection, love, rage, and also action. You’ll find all kinds of writing here, and a diversity of voices and styles, to remind us of the diversity of humankind and of our beautiful living earth.</description></item><item><title>2023 Showcase Submission Instructions</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023-showcase/submission-instructions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023-showcase/submission-instructions/</guid><description>With your Solarpunk vision for the planetary future in mind, please write a short story of up to 2,500 words and send it as an email (or Word/ PDF/ Google Doc email attachment) to XR Wordsmiths (xr-writers@protonmail.com) with the subject line ‘Solarpunk Showcase Submission 2023’.
Writers under the age of 18, please have your parents fill out a consent form for your entry. You can click on it here and please attach it with your submission.</description></item></channel></rss>