<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Honorable Mentions on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2021/stories/honourable-mentions/</link><description>Recent content in Honorable Mentions on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2021/stories/honourable-mentions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Green Wall</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/green-wall/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/green-wall/</guid><description>The light from the tall window glinted on the pincers. Between their finely-engineered points, Lin held a tiny, red-leaved oxalis. With a purposeful prod, she inserted it into the wad of sphagnum moss where the other red-leaved species were already taking root. Further back along the wall, where she had first begun, tides of green tendrils lapped against jade fractals. Glossy weeping figs sheltered verdant ferns, whose close-held scent reminded Lin of woodland streams.</description></item><item><title>Hanging Gardens of Babylon</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/hanging-gardens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/hanging-gardens/</guid><description>“What we’re looking at here,” he pulled the map down slightly, “is the only man-made wonder of the world to exist twice. Every other thing on this old list has been destroyed.”
We both took a look at the gates guarding the Hanging Gardens of Babylon. The posts were clearly composed of scrap metal forged into single, twisting rods. The gates reached high above our heads, weaving into each other like so many gleaming branches.</description></item><item><title>Meeting at the Giant Mushroom</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/meeting-mushrooms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/meeting-mushrooms/</guid><description>Lisa Kendrick brushed down her smart, grey skirt suit, then smoothed her perfectly styled hair. Pausing, she checked her makeup and gave her hair a second glance, then she nodded, satisfied that she still looked like she’d just stepped out of a salon. Then she stopped and thought. Then she sat down.
“I’m overdressed,” she told herself. Damn. She hadn’t wanted to fret, but there she was, fretting. She wanted to impress but she was probably going about it in completely the wrong way.</description></item><item><title>Rooted Ritual</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/rooted-ritual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/rooted-ritual/</guid><description>Paulo awoke to the sound of sizzling tomatoes being cooked by his grandmother in the kitchen of their two-bedroom apartment. Several seconds of serene silence passed before she sweetly beckoned him for breakfast.
“Paulo…. Paulo” she called, followed by several other soft murmurings that he couldn’t quite discern.
The air was crisp as beams of light filtered through the mosaic gaps of his slightly ajar window. He stretched, stirred, twisted and eventually rose to peer out across the vast landscape of pinkish clouds that were warmed by a golden coat from the early morning sun.</description></item><item><title>Seaweed</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/seaweed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/seaweed/</guid><description>The dark eye of the whale focused contemplatively on the thick clumps of seaweed streaming past. The fronds brushed up against her skin, which like her eye, took in the colour and shape of the fresh green plants. Blinking slowly, she rolled towards the surface, pulled a deep gasp of empty air into her lungs, turned her fins, and directed the movement and power of her body downwards.
Below in the depths, her family circled, noses touching tails, grandmothers of hundreds of years covered in thousands of barnacles brushing up against last year’s babies, smooth as silk and bright pale grey.</description></item><item><title>Sooty</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/sooty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/sooty/</guid><description>If there was one word to describe the city it was small. Tiny compared to the Fuel Era cities. Or at least the ruins of them. In the centre were the towers and the bigger buildings, not too dissimilar to the old cities. Just smaller. Every building had either a wind turbine on it or tracking solar array. When viewed from a distance it looked like a collection of potted flowers.</description></item><item><title>The Well-Trodden Path</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/well-trodden/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/well-trodden/</guid><description>“Where are they?” asked Blue, transferring into the cockpit. “How worried are we?” “They’re post-nuclear, pre-Universal,” replied Grey, projecting a zoomed-in view of the industrial complexes which studded the blue/beige planet they were orbiting. Blue performed the guttural vibrations which in their culture meant frustration, and complained: “Just once, I’d like to find a people we can talk with who don’t yet have the means and inclination to incinerate everything.”</description></item><item><title>Utopia in the Sewers</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/utopia-sewers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/stories/utopia-sewers/</guid><description>September 28th, Daylight. They have overtaken the surface for quite some time now. Their calendars say the year is 2089, ours 58. I do not know which one’s true. We are safe underground in a place the surface people call Esenyurt. They don’t come down, we don’t go up. Sewers run deep. They don’t allow us at the surface of the city. They send their nuclear waste and garbage down here.</description></item></channel></rss>