<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>11 and under on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/11-and-under/</link><description>Recent content in 11 and under on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/11-and-under/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Kids Who Made a Future</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/11-and-under/the-kids-who-made-a-future/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/11-and-under/the-kids-who-made-a-future/</guid><description>Once upon a time there was a girl who loved nature. But she could see that our world was in danger. That little girl was Phoebe. Her best friend Arianne also wanted to help the environment. One day they were sitting on the sofa thinking of ideas for what to plant in the garden, when Arianne had the best idea ever! “Phoebe, this is nothing to do with planting but what if we made a time machine to see how good or bad the pollution is?</description></item><item><title>The Light and Shadow of the Forest</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/11-and-under/the-light-and-shadow-of-the-forest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/11-and-under/the-light-and-shadow-of-the-forest/</guid><description>A blonde girl with a white dress walked through the forest, calling out to her parents, wishing they could hear her cries. Her name was Lily. She walked deeper and deeper into the dark forest. The trees all looked the same, with the same haunting era. She scrunched up her nose in disgust as she saw a fox, killed by a misplaced trap. She left it and kept walking. Tiny squeals sounded from a nearby withered bramble bush, she peeked in and saw a family of rabbits curling up around one another, the sight warmed her heart.</description></item><item><title>The Spirit of Christmas Future</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/11-and-under/the-spirit-of-christmas-future/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/11-and-under/the-spirit-of-christmas-future/</guid><description>Have you ever had spooky spirits haunting your dreams at night? Well you’re in for a rough ride if you haven’t. Fasten your seatbelt and hold on tight because your nightmares are about to come to life!
A young female teenager goes to sleep angrily on December 23rd. She tells her pet dog, “I don’t even want to celebrate Christmas this year.” Let’s rewind for a second. The girl, Eliana sits at the round dinner table and glares at her phone nonstop.</description></item></channel></rss>