<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>12–18 on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/12-18/</link><description>Recent content in 12–18 on XR Wordsmiths Solarpunk Storytelling Showcase</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/12-18/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Less Fear</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/12-18/less-fear/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/12-18/less-fear/</guid><description>JANUARY 14TH, 2123
The green vines climb and reach the top of the city’s skyline. Leaves and branches bursting out of the windows and balconies of a bright skyscraper – absorbing the light of the sun to power all of its inhabitants. There’s just as much life of flora as there is the life of people in the building. I look across the park to my right and see how the people have almost merged with the many native trees and plants that occupy the park, because there are always more plants than people – wherever you go in the city, whatever street, alley or hallway.</description></item><item><title>The Lost Chapter</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/12-18/the-lost-chapter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/12-18/the-lost-chapter/</guid><description>It was a rainy December afternoon on Cornelia Street. I walked into a small antique bookstore, the smell of dusty untouched books filled the air. My muddy shoes tracked across the vintage carpet as I silently strolled down the long corridor, admiring the stunning architecture and dark wooden bookshelves around me. The elegance of the bookstore enchanted me, and slowly, I wandered to the basement. It was as though time had stopped.</description></item><item><title>Tomorrow's Greatest Mystery</title><link>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/12-18/tomorrows-greatest-mystery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://solarpunk-storytelling.github.io/2023/stories/12-18/tomorrows-greatest-mystery/</guid><description>The night was warm, and Tim could hear cicadas singing in the distance. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s time to wake up.&amp;rdquo; he thought.
Tim&amp;rsquo;s bed, mostly made from mycelium and wood fibers. It was comfy, and getting up in the morning was one of the hardest things he had to do every day. It was his privilege. The sun&amp;rsquo;s warm light finally went through Tim&amp;rsquo;s windows as he got up. &amp;ldquo;Here we go again&amp;rdquo; he whispered to himself, cracking a smile.</description></item></channel></rss>